Think fast. Look alive. Die hard.
Die Hard: With a Vengeance is a action, thriller
film directed by John McTiernan.
New York detective John McClane is back and kicking bad-guy butt in the third installment of this action-packed
series, which finds him teaming with civilian Zeus Carver to prevent the loss of innocent lives.
McClane thought he'd seen it all, until a genius named Simon engages McClane, his new "partner"
-- and his beloved city -- in a deadly game that demands their concentration.
John McClane, played by Bruce Willis.
Zeus Carver, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Simon, played by Jeremy Irons.
Chief Walter Cobb, played by Larry Bryggman.
Joe Lambert, played by Graham Greene.
Ricky Walsh, played by Anthony Peck.
Die Hard with a Vengeance is a 1995 American action film directed and produced by John
McTiernan, written by Jonathan Hensleigh, and starring Bruce Willis as John McClane.
It is the sequel to Die Hard (1988) and Die Hard 2 (1990) and the
third installment in the Die Hard film series.
The film also stars Jeremy Irons and Samuel L.
Jackson, and features Graham Greene, Colleen Camp,
Larry Bryggman and Sam Phillips.
In the film, NYPD Lieutenant John McClane is embroiled in a plot by a mysterious terrorist calling himself “Simon” (Irons), who extorts the
city of New York by threatening to detonate several bombs unless McClane solves a series of games scattered across the city.
McClane reluctantly partners with a shopkeeper named Zeus Carver (Jackson), and learns the
terrorists plot to steal the gold bullion of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York.
Adapted from a spec script written by Hensleigh, Die Hard with a Vengeance was the first film in the series not directly based on a literary source material, and
the first not to be produced by Joel Silver and Lawrence Gordon after both producers had a fall-out with Willis, instead being produced by Andrew G.
Vajna’s Cinergi Pictures.
Principal photography took place in New York City and South Carolina.
The film was released on May 19, 1995 by 20th Century Fox and grossed $366.1 million worldwide, becoming
the highest-grossing film of the year, and initially received mixed reviews from critics.
However, the film has received positive reevaluation over time and is
now largely considered the best sequel in the franchise.
The film was followed by Live Free or Die Hard in 2007
and A Good Day to Die Hard in 2013.
The film explores themes of new york city, taxi, gold, helicopter, robbery.
The tone is intense.